Guide to the Angelo F. Semino Papers, 1856-1986
Department of Special Collections
Angelo F. Semino Papers,
1856-1986
Special Collections M0316
Semino, Angelo F.
2.75 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Angelo Semino, 1978, 1982, and 1986.
Biographical Note
Angelo F. Semino received his a.b. in mechanical engineering from Stanford in 1922.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of two separate types of material.
1. Land deeds for property in Mountain View where Mayfield Mall now stands, 1878-1926.
2. Original typed reports, xeroxes, reprints, and ms. notes on heat exchangers in the petroleum industry.
3. A transcript of an oral interview with Mr. Semino, 1978, which has information re both the above materials.
University Archives has Mr. Semino's class notes, 1919-1922.
Container List
- Land Deeds (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1. 1878, May 29.San Jose. Herrmann Bros., surveyors and Civil Engineers ADS description and holograph map of property in Santa Clara Co., Ca. Adjoining Rancho Rincon de San Francisquito, 3 pp.
    (3) with cover [not contemporary].
  - 2. 1878, June 6.Santa Clara Co., Ca. Indenture: Secondino Robles and Maria Antonia de Robles to Stefano Cordarro, Battista Bordi and Guiseppe Galini. Partially printed holograph deed to property southeast of Rancho Rincon de San Francisquito. Parties to deed signed with X. Signed by Geo. N. Yoell, notary and A.S. Williams, Deputy Recorder., 3pp.
    (4)
  - 3. 1878, June 7.Santa Clara Co. Stefano Cordano, Battista Bordi and Guiseppe Galini to Giovanni Nicora of the Mortgage Banking House of San Jose on the property described in No. 1. Partially printed document. Signed by the principals and Jas. R. Lowe, 4 pp.
    (5)
  - 4. 1878, Nov. 20.Santa Clara Co., Ca. Stefano Cordarro, Batista Bordi and Guiseppe Galini to Paolo DeMartini, Luigi Ratto, Fortunato Cordarro, Giocomo Ravegho and Vincenzo Petrocchi. Partially printed deed to property in Santa Clara Co. adjoining Rancho Rincon de San Francisquito. Signed by the principals and C. Piatti, Geo. W. LaPerri, [John L. McKibben.], 3pp.
  - 5. 1887, Nov. 30.[San Mateo Co.?] Jose A. Martinez to Pasquale Samina & Co. [sic.] Partially printed lease to portions of El Corte de Madera Rancho. Signed by the parties to the agreement, F.F. Fitzpatrick and J.F. Johnston., 3pp
    (3)
  - 6. 1894, Oct. 24.Mt. View. C. Piatti to Arata & Co. ADS. Receipt, 1p.
    (1)
  - 6a. 1894, Oct 24.Mt. View, ADS. Agreement between partners of Arata & Co. on distribution of property on dissolution of said company. ADS signed by Giovanni Ratto, Giacomo Rovegno, Giovanni DeCenedetti, Pasquale Semini, Guiseppe Arata, Giovanni Arata and C. Piatti., 2pp
    (2)
  - 7. 1894, Dec. 12.Santa Clara Co. Tax Collector to G. Arata & Co. Tax bill with attached receipt dated Dec. 12 [1894 or 1895].Signed [F.A. January], 1p
  - 8. 1899, Oct. 31Santa Clara Co. Tax Collector to P. Semini. Tax bill with attached receipt. Signed [A. Mullen], 1p
  - 9. 1902, Aug 15,Santa Clara Co., Ca. Lease. Pasquale Semino to Mok Hoong. TDS Typed lease of part of Arata Partition near the town of Mt. View... Signed by the parties and Garata and F. Bellarmi., 3pp.
  - 10. 1926, Oct. 27Santa Clara Co. Tax Collector, to P. Semino. Receipt signed Anthony H. Solari, 2pp
  - 11. 1926, Feb. 15Santa Clara Co. Tax Collector, to P. Semino. Receipt signed Geo. O. Frost, 2pp
- 1. 1923, June 18.San Jose, Ca. Abstract of Title Rancho Santa Rita or Rincon de San Francisquito, signed by A.W. Kerr. Traces history of property in Santa Clara Co., its ownership and use ca. 1856-1922.Plot map is included. (Box 1, Folder Folder 2)
- 1. 24 pg. transcript of oral interview with Mr. Semino done in 1978.Discusses early days on the Mountain View farm, time at Stanford, and time with Shell Oil Company. (Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
- Heat exchangers in the petroleum industry. Some reprints, xeroxes, original typed reprints, ms notes. 1920's - 1930's. (Box 2-5)